开萝尔∶是那个邮递员吗?那邮递员走了没有?
Carol: Is that the mail man?Was that the mail man leaving?
迈克∶什么!和你亲爱的哥哥连声招呼都不打?
Mike: What!Not even a hello, for your dear sweet brother?
开萝尔∶哥哥好!邮递员已经走了吗?
Carol: Hello!Was that the mail man leaving?
迈克∶开萝尔,你一点诚意也没有,让我觉得很受伤害.
Mike: Carol, your lack in sincerity wounds me.
开萝尔∶迈克,该死的邮件到哪里去了?
Carol: Mike, where's the stinking mail?
迈克∶就在那边台上呢!
Mike: It's right over there on the counter!
开萝尔∶这里也没有!没有!
Carol: It's not here again!It's not here!
迈克:不用担心,也许明天你就能收到那封来自纽约百老汇116号,
Mike: Well don't worry, Carol.
10027的信.
Maybe tomorrow you'll get that letter from err...a hundred
and sixteenth on Broadway, New York City, One double O two seven
开萝尔∶你有种.
Carol: You have it.
迈克∶已经有很多女人这样说过了.
Mike: A lot of women say that.
开萝尔∶迈克,把我的信给我,从哥伦比亚寄来的!
Carol: Mike, give me my letter from Columbia!
迈克∶等一下,你是说从哥伦比亚广播学校来的?
Mike: Wait, you mean Columbia School of Broadcasting?
不是什么哥伦比亚广播公司的附属学校或其他的不受重视的分站吧?
Not affiliated with the CBS network or its own unoperated stations!
开萝尔∶信到底在哪里,讨厌鬼?
Carol: Where's the letter, head louse?
迈克∶哦,记起来了,你指的是哥伦比亚大学!
Mike: Oh, you're talking about Columbia University!
是你申请的唯一一所大学!你百般努力,
The only college that you applied to!
费尽千辛万苦,就是为了能成为这个学校的一份子,对吗?
The place you have your over-worked heart set on, right?
开萝尔∶我想拿一把刀来!
Carol: I'm getting a knife!
迈克∶好了,好了,好了.如果我说我看见过这样一封通知书,你会...
Mike: OK, OK.OK, what if I have seen this alleged letter..
开萝尔∶厚厚的还是薄薄的?
Carol: Thick or thin?
迈克∶你在说你自己还是那封信?
Mike: You or the letter?
开萝尔∶迈克!那封信很薄吗,只有几句谢谢和客套的拒绝的话?还是厚厚的,
Carol: Mike!Was the letter thin, like a thanks but no thanks rejection,
表示可以接受我的申请,让我新学期去报到?哈!
or thick, like we'll see you in the fall acceptance?Ha!
迈克∶又来了,连一声谢谢都没有?
Mike: What, not even a thank you?
开萝尔∶幸好,和你的头一样厚,嘿嘿,应该是哥伦比亚大学的录取通知书.要不要嗅嗅,迈克?这可是你离名牌大学联盟最近的机会哦.(开始读信)
Carol: Thank goodness; thick like your head, like an acceptance to a real school.Wanna smell it Mike, I mean this is the closest you'll get to the Ivy League.(Reading from the letter)
"开萝尔,欢迎你来到哥伦比亚大学.学校将于1989年12月23日开学"十二月二十三号?啊,不!那不是秋天,是冬天.
Welcome, Carol Seaver, to the Columbia University Class of nineteen ninety three and a half
Your freshman orientation begins December twenty third, nineteen eighty nine." December twenty third?Oh no
It's not fall, that's winter
迈克∶这就是所谓的名牌大学?
Mike: And that's a real school?
杰森:(继续读信)"因此,由于新生太多,我们只好让一部分新生等到冬季学年才开学."
Jason: (Reading from the letter) "So, due to high enrollment we're forced to defer a certain amount of freshman, until the winter semester."
麦琪∶他们怎么能延误我做聪明的孩子呢?
Maggie: How dare they defer my brightest child?
迈克∶我...我是在房里呢.
Mike: I...I am in the room here.
杰森∶迈克,我们知道你在房里.麦琪,
Jason: We know that, Mike.Maggie, don't worry about it.
不必担心.只是推迟一个学期而已,又不是世界末日.
It's only for one semester and it's not the end of the world.
迈克∶你们最聪明的孩子可不会这么说.如果你们不想让我呆在这里,
Mike: It's not what your brightest child said.
就说话哈.
If you want me out of here, just say the word.
杰森和麦琪∶出去吧.
Jason and Maggie: The word.
迈克∶好吧.对了,
Mike: Alright, oh and look, by the way,
提醒一下,你们去楼上安慰开萝尔的时候,
if you're gonna go upstairs to cheer up Carol,
千万不要说什么"拒绝","失败者"或"完蛋"之类的词.
I advise you not to use words like, "reject", "loser" or "belly up."
你们想让我去厨房,对吗?
Kitchen, right.
麦琪∶可怜的开萝尔.
Maggie: Poor Carol.
杰森:亲爱的,我认为这对于开萝尔来说是非常重要的.这只是人生中的一个小困难,克服这些困难可以让我们更好的掌握自己的命运--更加自信的去面对困难.
Jason: Honey, I think the important thing for Carol, is to understand here,
is that this little hitch here,
is just one of those bumps in the rocky road of life,
which over the long haul makes us a better driver- confident we can handle
our rig.
麦琪∶杰森,我认为这些话对开萝尔一点用都没有.
Maggie: Jason, I don't think Carol's gonna have any use for truck talk.
开萝尔现在最需要的就是能和通情达理的父母开诚布公的谈谈.
What Carol needs is good old-fashioned straight-talking logic,
我上去找她.
from a sensible parent.I'll talk to Carol.
你去喝点东西,顺便把你的卡车加满油.
Why don't you grab a cup o' Joe and gas up your rig.
麦琪∶开萝尔.现在不是闹情绪的时候.
Maggie: Carol, this is no time for emotion.
你必须以分析的眼光来看待这件事情,因此,
You must force yourself to look at this analytically, so just dry your eyes...
别再哭了...你没有留眼泪?
They're dry!
开萝尔∶你好像很失望呀.
Carol: You sound disappointed.
麦琪∶耶……我的意思是说,不.我是说,因为你被……
Maggie: Ye...I mean, no.I mean, with you being rejec...
开萝尔∶被拒绝.妈妈,
Carol: Rejected.You can say it Mom, let's not run from it.
尽管说,别吞吞吐吐.我是说,
I mean, it's time for good old-fashioned, straight-forward logic,
现在是我们开诚布公的谈谈的时候了,你认为呢?
don't you think?
麦琪:这就是我为什么要提醒你关于你已经被哥伦比亚大学接受的原因.
Maggie: Whi...which is why I want to remind you that you have been accepted to Columbia.
开萝尔:这不是一件简单的事情.
Carol: Which is no small achievement.
麦琪:这不是一件简单的事情.
Maggie: Which is no small achievement.
开萝尔:只是我崎岖不平的人生道路上一些小颠簸而已,他们会让我成为更好的司机.
Carol: Which is just one of those bumps in the rocky road of life, that'll make me a better driver.
麦琪:我相信你能驾驶好你的卡车.
Maggie: Confident that you can handle your rig.
开萝尔:什么卡车?
Carol: What rig?
麦琪:宝贝,现在最关键的就是,
Maggie: Sweetheart.What's important here is that you don't feel like a
你不要总是觉得自己是个被拒绝的人,或者是一个垂头丧气的失败者,我们没有谁会这么想的.
reject, and a loser who went belly up.Not that anyone else is thinking that.
开萝尔:妈妈,别担心.我也没那么想.
Carol: Mom, everything's gonna be fine.
麦琪:真的没有?
Maggie: You're not just saying that?
开萝尔:你先听我说完我接下来3个月的打算嘛!我打算去阿尔福蓝登中级大学学习一个学期的双学位,
Carol: Wait till you hear how I'm gonna spend the next three months!
你也知道,那些工作对我来说太简单了...
Matriculating at Alf Landen Junior College.
还有,迈克也在那里.
And I'll take a double course load, 'cause the work couldn't be very
所以呢,就算我只学一半,
challenging...Mike goes there.
我也可以走的呀.我觉得这样不错哦.
And that way, even if only half my As are transferable, I'm doing just fine.
麦琪:看来,你根本就不需要我的安慰啦...
Maggie: So, you don't need me at all to...comfort you.
开萝尔:啊,妈妈,你是来安慰我的吗?
Carol: Oh Mom, is that why you came up here?
麦琪:是呀.
Maggie: Kind of.
开萝尔:要不要学"母女情深"里面的黛布拉温格和雪莉迈克雷恩一样,并排躺在床上,踢踢脚呢?
Carol: Well, wanna lay on the bed and kick our feet like Debra Winger and Shirley McLean in "Terms of Endearment"?
麦琪:不要!……就学一分钟也好.
Maggie: No!...maybe just for a minute.
本:我没觉得有什么不得了的啊.有这么长的一个暑假,
Ben: I just don't see what the big deal is.
开萝尔应该感到高兴才对呀.
I mean, Carol should be glad she's getting an extra long summer vacation.
杰森:本,希望越大,
Jason: Well Ben, it all comes down to expectations.
失望越大.
I mean, there's Carol, a straight A student,
你想想看,这件事情发生在开萝尔的身上,
and when she doesn't get welcomed, with open arms,
她可是个全优的学生,当她被自己所选择的大学拒之门外时,
to the college of her choice, well it's surprising.
当然是让人始料不及的.但是呢,
Mike on the other hand;
迈克就不一样了,
suppose Mike had been turned down by an Ivy League college,
如果他被哪所名牌大学拒之门外,我们就不会……你能把那边的芥末递给我吗?
well nobody would...Could you pass the mustard there.
开萝尔:嗨,西维尔家的男士门……迈克.
Carol: Hello Seaver men...Mike.
杰森:开萝尔,没想到你看上去好象还蛮不错的.
Jason: Carol, I didn't expect to see you so bubbly.
本:见鬼了!
Ben: Hell of a tub!
开萝尔:哦,那让我说什么呢?我呀,平静的很.
Carol: Well, what can I say?I'm resilient.
杰森:哦,麦琪,你和她谈过了?
Jason: Well, I see you talked to her.
开萝尔:这只是我崎岖不平的人生道路上的一段插曲而已.
Carol: This is just part of my journey down life's rocky road.
杰森:我想是我的劝告起作用了.
Jason: I see my advice worked out.
麦琪:事实上,我一字都没跟她提过.
Maggie: Really, I didn't use a word of it.
杰森:真的吗?那好吧.
Jason: Yeah, right.
开萝尔:迈克,你有蓝登学校的新课程表吗?
Carol: Mike, do you have the new Landen course catalogue?
迈克:当然.但我要用.
Mike: Yeah.But I'm using it.
开萝尔:你在用,不会是拿来垫你的桌子腿吧?
Carol: For what, to keep your table legs even?
迈克:呃,你要那个干什么?
Mike: Err...well why?
开萝尔:呵,我决定这个学期先在那里学学.
Carol: Well, I've decided to take some courses there this semester.
迈克:好呀.
Mike: Yeah, right.
开萝尔:我是认真的,迈克.
Carol: I'm serious Mike.
你和我都将被阿尔福蓝登大学秋季录取.
You and I will both be matriculating at Alf Landen this fall.
迈克:少来了,开萝尔!
Mike: Shh!Carol.
开萝尔:我说的都是真的.
Carol: It means, going there.
麦琪:她是认真的,迈克.
Maggie: She's not kidding, Mike.
杰森:她是认真的?开萝尔,你为什么要去那儿?迈....
Jason: She's not?Carol, why would you go there?Mi...I'm sorry, Mike.
抱歉,迈克,我无意诋毁你的...
I didn't mean to insult your ...
迈克:啊哈.
Mike: Aha.
开萝尔:那是你的学校.
Carol: It means, your school.
迈克:哦,哦!
Mike: Oh.Oh!
开萝尔:迈克,
Carol: Mike, don't worry.
别担心.我只不过是在那里呆几个月而已,
I'll only be there for a few months,
而你却可以在那里呆上个七年八年的.
and then you'll have your seven or eight years there to yourself.
迈克:我不想和你在同一个学校...
Mike: Well, I don't feel like having you matriculating all over my...
开萝尔:爸爸,我向你保证我不会学太多,我只是为下个学期的课程打点基础而已.
Carol: Dad, I'll grant you I won't learn much, but I'll pile up some credits for next semester.
杰森:恩,这么说来,就没有什么好不可思议的了.
Jason: Well, that makes a lot of sense...as usual.
本:有谁可以跟我说说,为什么迈克这几年无所事事,
Ben: I just want someone to explain to me,
而开萝尔却卖力的学习,
how come after all those years of Mike doing nothing and Carol working her...
结果两个人会要去上一样的大学呢?
working hard, how they could both end up at the same school ?
如果是这样的话,那我也没有学习的动力了.
I mean, this isn't giving me much of an incentive.
麦琪:本,其实呢,答案很简单,
Maggie: Well Ben, there really is a very simple answer, and it's one that...
就是...嘿嘿,我想你爸爸更愿意为你解答.
errm...your father would be happy to explain.
杰森:恩,我刚刚又想了一下,
Jason: Yes, well, I think that once again,
这都是看个人的期望了.
this just comes down to expectations.
还有...坦白说,
And...err...frankly I...err...wasn't expecting to answer this question.
我根本没想过会要回答这个问题.我认为你妈妈应该把她想要说的话都说出来,
I think what your mother wanted to say here, and she would have said it,
在看她来,不,
if she had the thoughts...not...not...
不..是她认为,
and she thinks, and she thinks that there is a college for everyone.
她认为一定有一个学校适合大家.毫无疑问,
And Alf Landen is certainly a great...you know...
阿尔福蓝登就是这样的一所,一所大学预科学校.
get ready for college, kind of college.
迈克:只是"大学预科学校?!"
Mike: A "get ready for college, kind of college?!"
杰森:迈克,迈克,我并不是说它不是一所大学;它算学分,还有不用花钱的建筑,但是...
Jason: Mike, Mike, I'm not saying that it's not a real college; it is credited, it has free standing buildings, but err...
本:那,这么说来,开萝尔这么多年的努力都付诸东流了?
Ben: So, you're saying, all Carol's hard work got her nowhere.
杰森:不,不,我当然不是这个意思.
Jason: No, I'm not!Carol's hard work got her into Columbia University...
正是因为开萝尔的努力,所以她最终还是被哥伦比亚大学录取了.
eventually.And Mike, if you had worked just a little bit harder,
迈克,如果你能多花一点心思在学习上,你也不至于要去那么……好的学校了.
you wouldn't be going to that...fine institution.
本:那,你的意思是说,迈克和开萝尔之所以要去那个学校,是因为他们都没有希望了吗?
Ben: So, you're saying that both Mike and Carol are going there because they're desperate.
杰森:没错!不!
Jason: Yes!!No!!No, I'm not saying that.
不,我才没有那么说.
I'm not, I'm saying that Alf Landen is a...
我的意思是说阿尔福蓝登是一个,是一个适合在人生道路上遭遇过挫折的人的地方.
it's a place that's suitable for many of the travelers down life's rocky road.
麦琪:够了,杰森!!别再提什么崎岖的道路了.
Maggie: Nice, Jason!!Whip out the rocky road thing again.
杰森:麦琪,
Jason: Maggie, come on!!
别这样!我只是想让我们的孩子们真正的明白,
I'm just saying that our kids, each of them, knows inside them self,
他们为什么会在这里.
deep down, exactly why they're there, right?
迈克:你说过如果我付不起房租,你就替我付的.
Mike: Well, you said if I didn't, you'd raise my rent.
开萝尔:我不要去那种烂地方!我这是在开自己的玩笑!
Carol: I can't go to that bozo place!I've been kidding myself!
我到底要做什么呀?
What am I gonna do?
麦琪:开萝尔!
Maggie: Carol!
杰森:开萝尔!
Jason: Carol!
迈克:好啦,好啦.没有人能控制我拉.
Mike: Oh fine.Fine, no-one stay here and console me.
本:还有我呢.
Ben: I stayed.
迈克:哈哈.
Mike: Yahoo.
麦琪:宝贝!
Maggie: Sweetheart!
开萝尔:我现在不想再提了.
Carol: I don't wanna talk about it.
杰森:但是,我们想和你谈谈.
Jason: Well, we want to talk to you about it.
开萝尔:就算我是被拒的人,是一个垂头丧气的失败者?
Carol: Even though I'm a reject, a loser who went belly up!
杰森:谁说的?
Jason: Who said that to you?
开萝尔:妈妈.
Carol: Mom.
麦琪:开萝尔,让我们来说说有用的话……
Maggie: Carol, let me communicate a sense of perspective here and...
杰森:开萝尔,你妈妈只是想跟你说……
Jason: I think what your Mom is trying to say Carol...
开萝尔:什么都不要说了,爸爸.
Carol: You too Dad.
现在别人说什么和做什么,对我来说,都没有意义了.
There is nothing that anybody can say or do for me right now.
杰森:都没有了?
Jason: Nothing?
开萝尔:没有了.
Carol: Nothing.
麦吉:要不要我帮你把中午饭拿上来?
Maggie: Can I bring you up your lunch.
开萝尔:好.还有盐湖苏打水.
Carol: Yes...and a Salt lake Soda.
麦琪:要柠檬吗?
Maggie: With a lemon?
开萝尔:谢谢妈妈.
Carol: Oh Mom.
杰森:开萝尔,在一生中……
Jason: Carol, on the interstate of life...
开萝尔:你刚才在楼下说的话很有道理.我怎么能去与牢房有互换学生项目的学校读书呢?
Carol: You're so right about what you said downstairs.
I mean, how could I go to a school that has an exchange program with a
prison?
杰森:那只不过是学习项目而已,据你哥哥所说,很多女孩子都能逆转她们的人生.
Jason: Look here, that's a work-study program, and from what your brother tells me, a lot of those girls have been able to turn their lives around.
开萝尔:但是,爸爸,我的成绩那么好,我是那么的优秀!我觉得一点也不公平,我认为我的人生已经到头了!结束了!全都结束了!开萝尔安尼西维尔的计划和一切的一切都化为泡影了!
Carol: But I got good grades, Dad!Perfect grades!I mean, this isn't fair, I feel like there is nothing I can do with my life right now!It's over!Finished!The end of the line...for Carol Anne Seaver!All my plans, gone with the wind!
杰森:宝贝,你不觉得自己有点太孩子气,太情绪化了吗?
Jason: Sweetheart, aren't you being a tad, over dramatic?
开萝尔:情绪化!情绪化!那麻烦告诉我,当一个人对生活没有任何希望的时候,什么样的反映才算正常呢?
Carol: Over dramatic!Over dramatic!Well excuse me, I mean, what is the acceptable response to when one's life has been snuffed out?
杰森: 宝贝,别这样了!只不过就3个月的时间而已!
Jason: Oh come on honey!I mean, it's only for three months!
开萝尔:3个月没有论文,没有测试,没有家庭作业,没有同学的羡慕!
Carol: For three months without papers or tests or homework; without the jealousy of my peers!!
杰森:你要明白,除了学校,还有另外一种生活.
Jason: You know there is a life, outside of school.
开萝尔:爸,别想忽悠我!
Carol: Dad, stop talking crazy!
杰森:开萝尔,你想想,
Jason: Well, Carol, you know, there's gonna come a time in your life,
总有一天,你是要离开学校的.
when school isn't part of it.
开萝尔:什么时候?
Carol: When?
杰森:那我问你,你读完哥伦比亚大学后,要做什么?
Jason: Well, what do you plan to do after Columbia?
开萝尔:继续读研究生.
Carol: Go to graduate school.
杰森:恩,那读完研究生后呢?
Jason: Yeah, and after that?
开萝尔:读博士.
Carol: Get my doctorate.
杰森:再接着呢?
Jason: And then what?
开萝尔:博士学位还不够吗?
Carol: A doctorate's not enough for you?
杰森:开萝尔,
Jason: I have an idea, Carol.
我知道在接下来的3个月里该让你去做什么了!
I think I know exactly the best way for you to spend the next three months!
你可以去世界上最大的大学!
You should be going to the biggest university in the world!
开萝尔:在俄亥俄州吗?
Carol: Ohio, State?
杰森:不,是工作的地方!
Jason: No, the work place!
开萝尔:工作的地方在哪里呢?
Carol: Where's that?
杰森:开萝尔,就在你周围.
Jason: It's all around you, Carol.
开萝尔:爸爸,你又说疯话了.
Carol: Dad, you're talking crazy again.
杰森:开萝尔,我没有胡说,我说的是社会大学.
Jason: Carol, no, I'm talking about the University of Life.
开萝尔:是一所宗教学院吗?
Carol: Is this a religious institution?
杰森:开萝尔,去找一份工作吧!
Jason: Carol, get a job!
开萝尔:找工作?
Carol: A job?
杰森:正是!
Jason: Yes!Come on!
现在是你见识外面世界的时候了;你不得不承认,在学校外面,
It's time you learnt a little bit about the world outside the classroom;
还有另外一种生活!
there is one, you know!
开萝尔:那我还不如去阿尔福蓝登.
Carol: I'd rather go to Alf Landen.
杰森:嗨,你有什么好怕的呢?只不过一个学期而已.拿出勇气来!别去学校了!!浪费一点时间也无所谓!
Jason: Hey, what are you afraid of?It's only for one semester.Have some guts!Be a quitter!Drop out of school!!Come on!The mind can be a beautiful thing to waste!
麦琪:我错过了一段好戏吗?
Maggie: I missed an awful lot, didn't I?
雇佣中介:总的来说,西维尔小姐,
Employment Agent: So, Miss Seaver, to sum up,
你以前都没有做过任何的兼职,也没有利用暑假打过工,
you've never had a part-time job,
也就是说,
you've never had a summer job and you have no job skills at all,
你没有任何的工作经验,对吗?
is that right?
开萝尔:我帮人照看过一次,两次小孩子.
Carol: Well, I did some baby sitting once...twice, really.
雇佣中介:两次.
Employment Agent: Twice.
开萝尔:好了,就写一次好了.不算真正的两次.有一次因为小孩子不见了,所以,他们没有支付报酬给我,总的来说,他还不错,虽然有次不小心把油漆弄掉了.
Carol: OK.Once.Twice is not really true.I mean, they didn't pay me 'cause the kid took off.He was fine though, once they got the paint off.
雇佣中介:让我看看,有没有比较简单的,差一点的工作.
Employment Agent: Let me check the unskilled, miscellaneous jobs.
开萝尔:出什么问题了?
Carol: What's the matter?
雇佣中介:哦,我总是无法回到主菜单.
Employment Agent: Oh, I always have trouble getting back to the main menu.
开萝尔:那里.
Carol: There.
雇佣中介:你会用这个程序吗?
Employment Agent: Are you familiar with this program?
开萝尔:不会,但是这不过是一个简单的二进位语言而已.
Carol: No, but this is a simple, binary language.
雇佣中介:啊哈.现在怎么样回到技术工作菜单呢?
Employment Agent: Aha.Now could you punch up, skilled jobs?
开萝尔:那里.
Carol: There.
雇佣中介:还有一个文字处理的副标题.
Employment Agent: Another subheading, word processing.
开萝尔:没问题,我们现在要找什么呀?
Carol: Sure.What are we looking for?
雇佣中介:找一份适合熟悉电脑的人做的工作.
Employment Agent: A job for someone very skilled with computers.
开萝尔:我还以为在替我找工作呢.哦!
Carol: But, I thought we were looking for a job for me.Oh!
杰森:乖,你会喜欢的,会喜欢的!
Jason: Oh, you're gonna love it, you're gonna love it!
本:你曾经也是这样对我的吧,爸爸?
Ben: Did you have to do that with me too, Dad?
迈克:本,没有啦,你总是喜欢咬自己的脚趾头.
Mike: No Ben, we had to stop you from gnawing your foot off.
麦琪:开萝尔马上就要下楼了,记住,要多说些鼓励的话!
Maggie: Carol's on her way down, and I want you boys to be very supportive.
迈克:给我C吧!给我A吧!
Mike: Give me a C!Give me an A!
杰森:配合点,迈克.
Jason: Subtler, Mike.
迈克:那给我一个R吧!
Mike: Give me an R.
麦琪:等着瞧我给开萝尔买的职业装.
Maggie: Wait till you see the outfit, I bought Carol.
开萝尔:大家好.
Carol: Hi.
杰森:我从来没见过这样的套装.
Jason: I've never seen anything like it.
麦琪:开萝尔,你的出现一定会在那个公司引起轩然大波,
Maggie: Carol, I can just tell that you are gonna hit that company like
从此在出版界声名鹊起.
a ton of bricks and know the publishing world on its ear.
迈克:本,我刚才听到了最好笑的一个笑话,
Mike: Benny, I got the best joke right now and I can't do a thing about
但是,我却不能笑.
it.
开萝尔:妈妈,这个连最基本的工作都算不上.
Carol: Mom, it's not even an entry level job.
杰森:好啦,记住,千里之行,始于足下.
Jason: Well, just remember, from little acorns do the mighty oaks grow.
开萝尔:呵呵,在其他人还没有说别的鼓励的话之前,
Carol: Well, before anybody says anything else supportive,
让我们拭目以待,看我能不能坚持一天.
let's just see if I get through one day.
杰森:你肯定行.
Jason: You bet.
麦琪:完全没问题.我们都为你自豪.
Maggie: Absolutely.You're father and I are so proud of you.
开萝尔:谢谢,但是你们也为迈克自豪吧.我走啦.
Carol: Yeah.But you're proud of Mike too.Let's go.
本:她越来越懂事了.
Ben: She's got a point.
老板:正如我之前跟你说的,我只说一次---我喜欢整洁,
Boss: As I said before, I'm only gonna say this once- I like my page endings,
清楚的页面.
neat and clean.
开萝尔:整洁和清楚.
Carol: Neat and clean.
老板:如果你弄错一个单词,那你就不用来上班了.欢迎你的加入.
Boss: Split a word, lose your job.Welcome aboard.
开萝尔:明白,先生.如果是弄错一个标点符号呢?
Carol: Yes sir.And what about the punctuation?
老板:标点的校对不是我们的任务.
Boss: Ah.That is not our business.
由标点部门那些愚蠢的家伙来负责.哦,
That belongs to those punks in the punctuation department...period.
当我没说过.
Forget I said that.
从现在开始,你就和其他分页人员一起工作;他们不赞成我叫"女士们",
Now, you will sit here with our other page breaking persons;
They don't like me saying ladies anymore, since Big Al joined the group
大A1:没错!
Big Al: Yo!
老板:这就是你工作的阵地;不允许有任何的装饰品,图片,或纪念品,总之,不允许任何希奇古怪或好看的东西.
Boss: This is your work station; no decorations, no photographs, no mementos, nothing of wonder or beauty whatsoever.
开萝尔:是个老古董.他不会像他看起来的这么差劲吧?
Carol: Gee, he's tough.Is he as mean as he seems?
大A1:我一点也不怕他.
Big Al: He doesn't scare me.
开萝尔:(在她的头脑中)我紧张的双手都在颤抖;我为什么会这么看重这份工作呢?就算最坏的情况,我也只不过是被炒鱿鱼而已,那我一样可以去...我没有地方可去了.
Carol: (in her head) My hands are shaking; why do I care about this job?If the worst comes to worst, I'll get fired, then I'll just go to...I can't go anywhere.I've got no place to go.
老板:52页?3个小时,你才到52页?
Boss: Page fifty two?Three hours and you're only on page fifty two?
开萝尔:实在不好意思,我已经用我最快的速度在读了.
Carol: I'm sorry, I'm reading as fast as I can.
老板:读?我不是已经跟你说过几百次了吗?
Boss: Reading?!What have I told you page breakers a hundred times?
是分页,分页,不是读!
Page breakers:......No reading!!
开萝尔:抱歉.
Carol: Sorry.
Big Al: Ever since you got here, this place has gotten really tense
开萝尔:(在她的脑海中)这是在12年的学习生涯中,第一次有老师对着我大吼大叫.等等,他才不是我的老师,他是我的老板.哎,如果我继续发呆的话,他肯定会毫不犹豫的把我给开了.
Carol: (in her head) This is the first time in twelve years of school, I've ever had a teacher yell at me.wait a minute, he's not my teacher, he's my boss.Oh, if this keeps up he's gonna fail me for sure.
员工:吃饭了,吃午餐了.
Worker: Lunch, dear, lunch.
开萝尔:哦,抱歉.
Carol: Oh, sorry.
大A1:要和我共进午餐吗?
Big Al: Wanna have lunch with me?
开萝尔:哦,我承诺过我妈妈,我们一起的.
Carol: Oh, I promised my Mom, we'd have lunch.
大A1:太棒了,我们走吧.
Big Al: Great, let's go.
开萝尔:不,不,我是说我和我妈妈一起吃,不是和你.
Carol: No, I mean, my mom, not you.
大A1:哦.那半小时后见吧.
Big Al: Oh.See you in half an hour.
开萝尔:好的.等等,我们只有30分钟的午餐时间?
Carol: Good, right.Wait, we only get a half hour for lunch?
大A1:对呀.
Big Al: Oui oui.
麦琪:(打电话)你好.麦琪马龙.
Maggie: (on the phone) Hello, Maggie Malone.
开萝尔:妈妈,是我.
Carol: Hi Mom.
麦琪:哦,开萝尔,太好了!我一直在等你的电话呢.工作的感觉怎么样?
Maggie: Oh, Carol, great!I've been waiting for you to call.How's it going?
开萝尔:还好.不过我的老板是个脾气暴躁又古怪的人!
Carol: Fine, just fine.I mean, so I work for a tyrant!
让我盯着那些单词看,却不让我读出来!还有,
So I stare at words I'm not aloud to read!
So I'm sitting next to a guy named, Big Al...who's waving his egg at
me
麦琪:大A1?
Maggie: Big Al?
开萝尔:妈妈,我要挂了,
Carol: Mom, I gotta go, I only got twenty eight more minutes of my lunch hour.
我只剩下28分钟的吃饭时间了,只剩27分了.
Make that twenty seven.
麦琪:居然有人对我的宝贝挥舞他的鸡蛋.
Maggie: Somebody's waving his egg at my baby.
开萝尔:(在她的脑海中)还有一个小时,我就挺过可怕的第一天了.恩,离开学只剩下89天了.
Carol: (in her head) One more hour, and I'm through my first miserable day.Only eighty nine more to go.
大A1:你有病吗?你在读!
Big Al: Are you insane?You're reading!
开萝尔:喂,我发现了一个错误,读看看.
Carol: Well, I found a mistake!Read it.
大A1:我才不会读.
Big Al: I dare not.
开萝尔:就算分页正确,正文却是错的,那谁会去在意?
Carol: Who cares if the page break is right and the text is wrong?
老板:我会!
Boss: I do!
大A1:我们本来可以相安无事的.
Big Al: We could have been so damn good together.
老板:你为什么不坐下来?有问题吗?
Boss: You're standing.You're not supposed to be standing.Is there a problem?
开萝尔:没有.
Carol: No problem.
老板:好.
Boss: Good.
大A1:聪明.
Big Al: Smart move.
开萝尔:不,事实上这里有一个问题.
Carol: Yes, there is a problem.
我不在意是否被你开除,但是,
I don't care if you fire me, but yes I've been reading.
我要说的是,我一直在读这些单词,因为我从四岁就开始读了,
Well it's hard to stop when you've been doing it since you've been four
所以,要我改掉这个习惯不是简单的事情.
years old.
老板:我经常说的是-我只说……
Boss: Like I always say- I'm only gonna say this...
开萝尔:你看这里!就是这里."
Carol: Look at this!Right here; the term "macroeconomics" is being misused.
宏观经济"这个词用错了.作者所写的是关于老年人的购买能力的问题,
The author's writing about the buying power of senior citizens,
而大家都知道,这应属于"微观经济"的范畴.
and everybody knows that's microeconomics.
作者是个很有智慧的人,因此,
And he's a very intelligent writer, so it has to be a typo.
我想可能是打印的错误.或者说,
Oh, right, maybe not very intelligent, I mean,
是作者的错误,用站不脚的例子来支持他提出的观点.
the supply side theory was supported with very weak...
老板:我马上去找校对室.
Boss: I'm calling the proof reading room.
大A1:你死定了.
Big Al: You're dead.
老板:自从发生科林事件后,我就一直想强迫他们注意类似的错误.
Boss: I've been wanting to rub their noses in something like this,
你叫什么?
ever since the Colin Incident.What's your name?
大A1:大A1.
Big Al: Big Al!
老板:没问你.问她呢.
Boss: Not you.Her.
开萝尔:西维尔.开萝尔西维尔.
Carol: Seaver.Carol Seaver.
老板:漂亮的纠错,西维尔.你们应该向她学习.
Boss: Nice catch, Seaver.You could all learn something from her.
大A1:教我吧.
Big Al: Teach me.
杰森:宝贝,你回来了.
Jason: Hey, honey, you're home.
麦琪:不要跟说那么肉麻的话!
Maggie: Don't "honey you're home" me!
杰森:有问题吗?
Jason: What?
麦琪:你居然穿着围裙,这么若无其事的站在这里……
Maggie: Well, you stand there so poised and so proper in your apron...
杰森:对呀.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:哈!说什么去上社会大学!
Maggie: Attend the university of life!
说什么能浪费一点时间也是件不错的事情!
The mind can be a beautiful thing to waste!Ha!
杰森:慢着……
Jason: Wait...
麦琪:现在好了,她去了乱七八糟的店里上班,
Maggie: So, off she goes to some sweat shop where some guy, named Big Al,
还有叫大A1的男人朝她挥舞鸡蛋……
is waving his egg at her.
杰森:亲爱的,我不明白……
Jason: Honey, I'm not following...
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Oh Jason, just do me one favour;
拜托你,如果开萝尔身心俱惫的回来,
when Carol comes home broken and battered,
请你让我一个人去安慰她.
let me be the one who puts her back together.
杰森:行,行,我听你的.
Jason: Fine, fine, yes.
麦琪:开萝尔……
Maggie: Oh Carol...
开萝尔:长这么大以来,今天是我最开心的一天.爸爸,谢谢你跟我说的那一番话!
Carol: Today was the best day of my life.Daddy you were so right.Thank you.
我今天做了一次漂亮的纠错.麦琪:亲爱的,我回来了!00:21:18,900
I made a nice catch! Maggie: Hi honey, I'm home!